Kevin Pranoto

Location: Irvine, CA 92602; Email: kevinpranoto.dev@gmail.com; Phone: (949) 771-5490

SUMMARY

Skilled and experienced software engineer with 5 years of experience in developing and delivering software solutions. Expert in creating and maintaining full-stack applications. Proficient in various industry-standard programming languages and technology stacks. Extensive knowledge in distribution of large-scale systems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Skills: Java, TypeScript, Python, and C++.

Software Development Methodologies: Experience in being lead for Agile and Scrum methods.

Cloud Computing: Expertise across AWS technologies (certification listed below).

Database: Expertise in NoSQL (AWS DynamoDB) and in-memory (memcached) databases.

DevOps: Expertise with DevOps tools and practices such as Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment, and Infrastructure as Code using AWS CodePipeline, CDK, and others.

Microservices: Expertise with building, deploying, and managing microservice-based applications using Docker containerization, horizontal scaling with ECS and Kubernetes clusters.

Web Development: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and front-end framework React/Redux stack.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II, Amazon, Irvine, August 2022 to Present

- Develop and maintain core Alexa Notification, successfully serving billions of notifications per week.
- Improve services' operational readiness to 100% (internal metrics) by designing full CI/CD pipeline, wrote infrastructure as code using AWS CDK, improved integration and canary tests coverage.
- Developed scaling mechanism to successfully handle 130% max load during holiday traffic peaks.
- Lead design reviews for features and provide estimation for org level and team level goal setting.

Front-end Engineer II, Amazon, Irvine, October 2021 to August 2022

- Developed, maintained, and launched a low-code/no-code web application Amplify UI Builder.
- Designed API schema to save custom data types, and directly increased customer satisfaction.
- Implemented various features, fixed various bugs, and unblocked feature launch before target date.

Cloud Software Engineer, Nuxeo (acquired by Hyland), Irvine, January 2020 to October 2021

- Built a full-stack serverless application from zero to a key internal tool within first year of joining
- Designed and implemented tools to mitigate ops manual deployments, increasing deploy rate by 100X across all customers

C++ Software Engineer, Siemens PLM Software, Irvine, June 2018 to December 2019

- Maintained and modernized legacy C and C++ code from 1970s to today's standards (50 years).
- Developed scripts to analyze and chart test coverage of 200,000+ files, improving QA processes.

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Developer — Associate, valid from March 2021 to March 2024

Credential ID: JEWVSZYD1FEE1YWQ

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, University of California — Irvine, Graduated June 2019 GPA 3.61/4.0; Emphasis on Networked Systems; Dean's list; Sigma Alpha Phi (National Honors Society);